Mss.B.L493
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 7.0 Linear feet 17 upright boxes, 1 oversized folder, 1 digital record. (Box 1-17)
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Aug. 22, 1854; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
    Liege, A.L.S. 4p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) His publications. Natural history. Coleoptera. Entomology. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to Jno. L. Le Conte, Aug. 25, 1854; 5 1/4" x 8"; Girard, Charles, 1822-1895
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Aug. 25, 1854; 7" x 9"; Ibbetson, Frederick H.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Aug. 25, 1854; 8x5; Squier, E. G., (Ephraim George), 1821-1888
    New York. A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers Business.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Aug. 26, 1854; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    Beesleys Point, N.J., A.L.S.1p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Aug. 26, 1854 (?); 4 1/2" x 7"; Ibbetson, Frederick H.
    Montreal, A.L.S. 1p. illus.
  - Receipt to J[ohn] S[L.] Le Conte, Aug. 28, 1854; 5-1/4x8-1/4; Conover, Ralph
    Jersey City, A.D.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) For lumber and labor.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Aug. 28, 1854; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Milham, J.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards bill of lading for boxes shipped by John Leforge.
  - Letter to John L. LeConte, Aug. 28, 1854; 8 x 10; Venvill, William
    Letter accompanying certified check.
  - Letter to John [E.] Le Conte, Aug. 29, 1854; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Schott, Arthur, 1814-1875
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards map.
  - Letter to John L[awrence] Le conte, Philadelphia, Aug. 30, 1854; 8-3/4x7; Logan, Thos. M. (Thomas Muldrup), 1808-1876
    Sacremento, Cal., A.L.S. 4p.,add. (see Le Conte papers.) Is keeping meteorological records. Natural history discoveries. Asks for help for scientific work. Friendly letter. Originally B L493.3
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Sept. 2, 1854; 7-1/2x5; Guex, John A.
    Jersey City, A.L.S. 6p. (see Le Conte papers.) Lists items sent,by crates, of his entomological collections.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Sept. 3, 1854; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Guex, John A.
    Jersey City, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Hopes for his future.
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Sept. 5, 1854; 10-3/4x8; Guex, John A.
    Jersey City, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Plans to remove to Philadelphia. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Sept. 6, 1854; 7" x 9"; Ibbetson, Frederick H.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Sept. 10, 1854; 8x5; Squier, E. G., (Ephraim George), 1821-1888
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers Business.
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Sept. 19, 1854; 7x4-1/2; Guex, John A.
    Jersey City, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte Papers.) Is selling his effects prior to moving to Philadelphia.
  - List of debts owed in New Jersey, Sept. 19, 1854; 7-1/2x7-1/2; Guex, John A.
    Jersey City, A.D.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.)
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Sept.19, 1854; 8x5; Squier, E. G., (Ephraim George), 1821-1888
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers Business.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Sept. 19, 1854; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Raynard & Treadmill
    New York, L. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Will forward shipment as soon as possible.
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Sept. 24, 1854; 7-3/4x6-3/4; Guex, John A.
    Jersey City, A.L.S. 2p. In Pencil. (see Le Conte Papers.) Concerning his needs.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Sept. 25, 1854; 8x5-1/4; Patterson, Thomas C.
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Asks him to visit Mr. Guex as soon as possible.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Lecompt [sic], Sept. 28, 1854; 8x5; Andrews, Mrs.
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers. Concerning John A. Guex.
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Sept. 28, 1854; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Guex, John A.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Hopes to leave for Philadelphia.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Sept. 29, 1854; 8-1/4x5; Squier, E. G., (Ephraim George), 1821-1888
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Business.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Sept. 30, 1854; 7" x 8 3/4"; Ibbetson, Frederick H.
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte, Sept., 1854?; 7x4-1/2; Guex, John A.
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Notifies him of shipment.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Oct. 1, 1854; 7" x 9"; Verrvill, William
    [New York] A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Oct. 2, 1854; 8" x 10"; Couper, William, 1853-1942
    Toronto, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Oct. 3, 1854; 8-1/4x5; Squier, E. G., (Ephraim George), 1821-1888
  - Letter to Jno. L. Le Conte, Oct. 9, 1854; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Oct. 16, 1854; 5" x 8"; Couper, William, 1853-1942
    Toronto, A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to John [L.] Le Conte, Oct. 16, 1854; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Wild, J. P.
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning the coleoptera collected in the West.
  - Letter to Jo[hn L. Le Conte?], Oct.22, 1854; 4" x 5 1/4"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Oct. 23, 1854; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Wild, J. P.
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Oct. 24, 1854; 8x5; Cooper, William, 1798-1864
    Toronto, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Entomology. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Oct. 25, 1854; 4" x 6"; Girard, Charles, 1822-1895
  - Letter to John L. Leconte, Oct. 26, 1854; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
  - Letter to Major John [E.] Le Conte, Nov. 1, 1854; 5" x 8"; Squier, E. G., (Ephraim George), 1821-1888
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Contains a note from P. T. Woodbury.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Nov. 3, 1854; 8-1/4x5; Squier, E. G., (Ephraim George), 1821-1888
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Nov. 4, 1854; 5" x 8"; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Nov. 5, 1854; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Apetz, Heinrich
    A.L.S. 3p. In German. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomological subjects. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to Jo[h]n L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Nov. 11, 1854; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Will ship him the new coleoptera. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Nov. 14, 1854; 8-1/4x5; Squier, E. G., (Ephraim George), 1821-1888
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Nov. 18, 1854; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Wild, J. P.
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards coleoptera. Entomology. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Dec. 1, 1854; 8x5; Kirtland, J. P., (Jared Potter), 1793-1877
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Natural history. Entomology. Friendly letter. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Dec. 10, 1854; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
    Liege, A.L.S. 3p. and end. In French.
  - Certification that there are no claims against the property of John Eisenbrey, Dec. 12, 1854
    5 certification forms, 1 letter.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Dec. 18, 1854; 9x7-1/4; Hammond, Ogden
    Charleston, S.C., A.L.S. 2p. (See Le Conte papers.) Asks him to forward a box which he left with a friend, now deceased. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to Jo[h]n L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Dec. 28, 1854; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    A.L.S. 1P. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards draft on his account. Originally B L493.2
    Dr. Lester D. Stephens believes this item to be dated 1854. (June 11, 1974) Originally dated 1883.
  - Letter to John [L.] Le Conte, 1854; 7" x 9"; Ibbetson, Frederick H.
    Montreal [ca.]. A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to John [L.] LeConte, ca. 1854; 8 x 10; Ibbetson, Frederick H.
    Letter regarding Coleoptera.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Jan. 1, 1855; 4 1/2" x 7 1/4"; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Jan. 9, 1855; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    Berlin, L. 4p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Jan. 15/27, 1855; 8 1/4" x 11"; Chaudoir, M. de (Maximilien), baron, 1817-1881
    A.L.S. 4p. In French.
  - Letter to J.L. Leconte, Jan. 16, 1855; 5" x 8"; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Feb. 1, 1855; 5" x 8"; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Feb. 1, 1855; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Hammond, William Alexander, 1828-1900
    Fort Riley, Kansas territory, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Feb. 2, 1855; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Ames, Frank
    San Diego, Cal.; A.L.S. 2p. (see LeConte papers.) Concerning his property in California.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Feb. 5, 1855; 7x4-1/2; Kendall, E. Otis (Ezra Otis), 1818-1899
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Asks him to dinner to visit and discuss entomology.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Feb. 8, 1855; 8-1/2x7; Hammond, E.
    Charleston, S.C., A.L.S. 6p. (see Le Conte papers.) Asks him to have an aquarium made for him.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Washington, Feb. 13, 1855; 8x5; Kirtland, J. P., (Jared Potter), 1793-1877
    Cleveland, A.L.S. 2p.and add.: "Care of Prof. A.D. Bache. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning difficulties with a publication. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Feb. 23, 1855; 8-1/2x7; Hammond, Bessie
    Charleston,S.C., A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Suggestions as to how to arrange an exhibition case for living animals.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n L. Leconte, Philadelphia, Feb. 24, 1855; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning lithographic plates for a publication. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Feb. 24, 1855; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S.with initials. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Is busy with the Smithsonian. Friendly letter. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Feb. 26, 1855; 6 3/4" x 8 1/4"; Sloat, Leslie W.
    San Francisco, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le C[onte], Feb. 27, 1855; 8x5; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers) Concerning publications. Coleoptera. Refers to Agassiz. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], March 8, 1855; 8x5; Duyckinck, George L. (George Long), 1823-1863
    New York A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers Asks him to check proofs of his article on the APS. Has asked Trego to do the same. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], March 9, 1855; 8x5; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Publications he has received for various persons and institutions, including the U.of P. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, March 19, 1855; 5 1/4" x 8"; Motschulsky, Victor de
    St. Petersburg, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French.
  - Letter to Jno. L. Le Conte, April 5, 1855; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, April 19, 1855; 5" x 8"; Hammond, Ogden
    Charleston, S.C., A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to Dr. [J.L. Le Conte ?], April 20, 1855; 8" x 10"; Rogers, Fairman, 1833-1900
    U.S. Coast survey camp, Key Biscayne, Florida, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], April 27, 1855; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, April 28, 1855; 8" x 10"; Hammond, Ogden
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], May 4, 1855; 7x4-1/2; Maclur, William L.
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning Guex. Refers to Haldeman.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, May 8, 1855; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology.
  - Letter to Jno. L. Leconte, May 9, 1855; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
  - Letter to Jno. L. Leconte, May 12, 1855; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    Washington, (?). A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, May 19, 1855; 5" x 8"; Hammond, Ogden
    Charleston, S.C., A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, May 25, 1855; 5" x 8"; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895
  - Letter to [John E.] Le Conte, May 26, 1855; 7-3/4x5; G. P. Putnam & Co.
    New York, L. 1p. (see Le Conte papers Concerning his receipt of the Transactions of the Royal Society of London.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, May 31, 1855; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
  - Letter to Dr. [J.L.] Le Conte, June 10, 1855; 5" x 8"; Hall, James, 1811-1898
    Albany, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], June 11, 1855; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Murray, Andrew, 1812-1878
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], June 16, 1855; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
  - Letter to J. L. Le Conte, June 23, 1855; 5" x 7 1/2"; Moore, George Henry, 1823-1892
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], July 30, 1855; 8x5-1/4; Sayre, Lewis A. (Lewis Albert), 1820-1900
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Urges him to join the party in watching the laying of the "submarine telegraph." Refers to Agassiz and O.W.Holmes as possible guests in the party.
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Aug. 2, 1855; 8" x 10"; LeConte, Joseph, 1823-1901
    Athens, Ga., A.L.S. 2P.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Sept. 13, 1855; 6" x 8"; Melsheimer, Friedrich Ernst, 1782-1873
    Dover, Pa., A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Le Conte, Sept. 15, 1855; 5" x 8"; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Sept. 20, 1855; 7-3/4x5; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    Cloverden, A.L.S.with initials. 1p. (see Le Conte Papers.) Has a box of bugs for him. "Are you sure they are all dead?" Originally B L493.2
  - List of entomological specimens sent to John L. Le Conte through B. A. Gould, Sept., 1855; 9-3/4x8; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    D. 1p.and end. (see Le Conte papers.)
  - Letter to John L. LeConte, Oct. 4, 1855; 8x10
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Nov. 6, 1855; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    Berlin, A.L.S. 5p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Nov. 20, 1855; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Wild, J. P.
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomological comments.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Nov. 25, 1855; 6-1/2x4; Steiner, Lewis Henry, 1827-1892
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards patented item for tape-worms. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John [L.?] Le Conte, Dec. 4, 1855; 8" x 10 1/2"; Poey, Felipe, 1799-1891
  - Letter to Dr. [J.L. Le Conte ?], Dec. 12, 1855; 5" x 8"; Melsheimer, Friedrich Ernst, 1782-1873
    Dover, York co., Pa., A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Dec. 27, 1855; 7-1/4x5-1/2; Ziegler, Daniel P., 1823
    York, Penna., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Will exchange his insects for publications, or duplicates of insects, with the Academy.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n L. Leconte [sic], Jan. 3, 1856; 11-1/4x9; Apetz, Johann Heinrich, 1794-1857
    Attenburg, A.L.S. 2p.,add. (see Le Conte Papers.) Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Jan. 19, 1856; 7x4-1/2; Hewitt, W. W. (William W.)
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Has returned from the West. Wishes he could visit.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Jan. 21, 1856; 10x7-3/4; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge Mass., A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology.
  - Letter to John [L.] Le Conte, Feb. 4, 1856; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Truqui
    Mexico, A.L.S. 4p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) His interest in entomology and coloeptera.
  - Letter to [John L. LeConte], Feb. 4, 1856; 7-1/2x5
    In French. Regarding Mexico, California, Coleoptera.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Feb. 9, 1856; 6x4; Morrison, James
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers Concerning various collections of insects and his hope of going on an entomological expedition in the U.S. with him.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Feb. 12, 1856; 8x6-1/4; Uhler, Philip R. (Philip Reese), 1835-1913
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Thanks for helping him with the publication. Entomological news.
  - Letter to Johnnie [J. L. Le Conte ?], Feb. 22, 1856; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, March 12, 1856; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Motschulsky, Victor de
    St. Petersburg, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards, through Osten Sacken, certain insects. Gives his correct address.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], March 13, 1856; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
    Liege, A.L.S. 4p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomological news.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, March 17, 1856; 8x5; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    New Orleans, A.L.S.with initials. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning a shipment of bugs.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, March 26, 1856; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    A.L.S. 6p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, April 2, 1856; 7x4-1/4; Mackenjaskne, W.
    St. Johns, Newfoundland, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning his collection of insects. Asks for names and titles of works on entomology.
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Le Conte, April 15, 1856; 5" x 8"; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
  - Letter to J.[L.?] Le Conte, April 26, 1856; 5" x 8"; Chaudoir, M. de (Maximilien), baron, 1817-1881
  - Letter to Dr. John [Lawrence] Leconte, May 4, 1856; 8" x 10"; Gibbs, George, 1815-1873
    Fort Steilacoon, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [John Lawrence] LeConte, May 8, 1856; Gould, Benjamin A., (Benjamin Apthorp), 1787-1859
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 2p. Acknowledges LeConte's earlier letter. Speaks of Frazer, Henry and Espy. Mentions the cause of his indigestion "night before last."
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, May 12, 1856; 8" x 10"; Hammond, William Alexander, 1828-1900
    Fort Riley, Kansas ter., A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [John L.] LeConte, May 17, 1856
    Refers to LeConte's letter of the 19th.
  - Letter to J[ohn L.] Le Conte, May 19, 1856; 7-3/4x6-1/2; Glover, Townend, 1813-1883
    Washington, L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Has sent items of hemipterae to be named by Haldeman.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte?], May 24, 1856; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Murray, Andrew, 1812-1878
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Le Conte, May 26, 1856; 4" x 6"; Thomson, James
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, May 30, 1856; 6 1/2" x 8"; Kennicott, Robert, 1835-1866
    West Northfield, Ill., A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to Jno. L. Le Conte, June 2, 1856; 5" x 8"; Stauffer, Jacob, b. 1808
    Mount Joy, A.L.S. 2p. illus.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, June 3, 1856; 8" x 10"; Grant, F. W. (Frederick William), 1834-1902
    Coldwater, nr. Orillia, C.W., A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, June 5, 1856; 5" x 7 1/2"; Uhler, Philip R. (Philip Reese), 1835-1913
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, June 15, [1856?]; 6 1/2" x 8"; Kennicott, Robert, 1835-1866
    West Northfield, Ill., A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to Jno. L. Le Conte, June 17, 1856; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Stauffer, Jacob, b. 1808
    Mount Joy, A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], June 23, 1856; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Murray, Andrew, 1812-1878
    Edin[burgh], A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, June 29, 1856; 5" x 8"; Hammond, William Alexander, 1828-1900
    Fort Riley, Kansas Ter., A.L.S. 8p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], June 30, 1856; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
    Liege, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, July 5, 1856; 4 1/2" x 7"; Hammond, William Alexander, 1828-1900
    Fort Riley, K[ansas] T[erritory]; A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], July 6, 1856; 6" x 7 1/4"; Vésey, Louis de
    Fort Riley, Kansas, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], July 12, 1856; 7x6; Vésey, Louis de
    Fort Riley, Kan., A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for his publication and will send coleoptera to him.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Aug. 13, 1856; 8" x 10"; Whitaker, Benjamin
    Warsaw, Ill., A.L.S. 2p. and end.
  - Letter to Dr. [J.L. Le Conte], Aug. 24, 1856; 5" x 8"; Hammond, William Alexander, 1828-1900
    Fort Riley, K[ansas] T[erritory], A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Sept. 5, 1856; 5" x 8"; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    Cambridge, [ca.] A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to Jno. L. Le Conte, Sept. 6, 1856; 4 1/2" x 7"; Steiner, Lewis Henry, 1827-1892
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [J.L.?] Le Conte, Sept. 16, 1856; 4 1/2" x 7"; Steiner, Lewis Henry, 1827-1892
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [John L.Le Conte], Sept. 24, 1856; 7x5-3/4; Vésey, Louis de
    Ft. Riley, A.L.S. 3p. Forwarded entomological specimens.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Oct. 1, 1856; 4 1/2" x 7"; Osten-Sacken, C. R. (Carl Robert), 1828-1906
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Oct. 8, 1856; 5" x 8"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
  - Letter to Jo[h]n L. Le Conte, Oct. 19, 1856; 12-1/2x8; Rathvon, S. S., (Simon Snyder), 1812-1891
    Lancaster, Penna., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning De Saussure. Concerning his entomological collections.
  - Letter to John [L.] Le Conte, Oct. 23, 1856; 8x5; Peirce, Benjamin, 1809-1880
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Asks that he borrow a volume from the APS for him.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Oct. 23, 1856; 4 1/2" x 7"; Steiner, Lewis Henry, 1827-1892
  - Letter to Johannes [John L.] Le Conte, Nov. 10, 1856; 7x4-1/2; Steiner, Lewis Henry, 1827-1892
    Baltimore, A.L. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Wishes that he and Sclator would visit, and perhaps stay a while, with him.
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Nov. 15, 1856; 7x4-1/2; Rogers, William Barton, 1804-1882
    Paris, A.L. 4p. Informs him of a perfect preservative for his insects.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Nov. 15, 1856; 6" x 7"; Vésey, Louis de
    Fort Riley, K.T., A.L.S. 8p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Nov. 16, 1856; 8x5; Hammond, William Alexander, 1828-1900
    A.L.S. 3p. Hopes to lay a paper before the Academy of Natural Sciences. Gyroscopes. Recommends a man for membership in the academy. Originally B L493.4
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Nov. 17, 1856; 5" x 8"; Hammond, Ogden
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Dec. 6, 1856; 8x6-1/2; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, Mass., ca. L.in hand of Mrs. Agassiz. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) States his belief of open Arctic seas, since whales live there.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Dec. 16, 1856; 4 1/2" x 7"; Osten-Sacken, C. R. (Carl Robert), 1828-1906
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to J.[L.?] Le Conte, Dec. 20, 1856; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    Berlin, A.L.S. 5p. and add.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Dec. 20, 1856; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Casas, J. Victor
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Le Conte papers.) Acknowledges parcel for the Naturforschende Gesellchaft, Leipzig. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to Jno. L. Le Conte, Dec. 20, 1856; 4 3/4" x 7 1/4"; Steiner, Lewis Henry, 1827-1892
  - Sketches of insects (3), [1856?]; Le Conte, John L. (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    D. 3p. Various sizes. (see Le Conte papers.) Originally B L493.4
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Jan. 15, 1857; 8-1/4x5; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Gives date of arrival in Philadelphia and asks him to join him. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Jan. 18, 1857; 5" x 8"; Hammond, William Alexander, 1828-1900
    Fort Riley, K.T., A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Jan. 21, 1857; 7-3/4x4-3/4; Christern, Frederick W.
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Lists arrangements for forwarding and receiving parcels. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to Dr. [J.L. ?] Le Conte, Jan. 31, [1857?]; 8" x 10 1/2"; Kennicott, Robert, 1835-1866
    Racine, Wis., A.L.S. 4p.